In 2166, an immortal
tyrant named Vandal Savage
2166년, 불멸의 폭군
반달 새비지는
conquered the world and
murdered my wife and child.
세상을 정복하고
내 아내와 아들을 살해했다
I have assembled an elite team
to hunt him throughout time
난 그자를 막기 위해
최정예 팀을 모았지만
and stop his rise to power.
Unfortunately, my plan is opposed
내가 충성을 맹세했던 의회는
계획에 반대했다
by the body I'd sworn
my allegiance to...
The Time Masters.
타임 마스터들...
In the future, my friends
may not be heroes,
미래에 이들은
영웅이 아닐진 몰라도
but if we succeed,
성공한다면
they will be remembered as legends.
'전설'로 기억될 것이다
Previously on "Legends of Tomorrow"...
지난 회
'레전드 오브 투모로우'
You need to learn to
embrace your human side.
너의 인간성을 받아들여
And what if that side of me is gone?
더 이상
존재하지 않는다면?
What if she doesn't exist anymore?
저더러 교수님 명령에
복종만 하라는 거잖아요
No, this is a dictatorship.
You get to call all the shots,
and I get to take all the shots.
The most powerful evil
the world has ever known
가장 강력한 악이
냉전 시대의 공산주의자가 됐군
has just gone Red at the
height of the Cold War.
Valentina Vostok?
- 발렌티나 보스톡...
- 소련 파이어스톰을 만들고 있었어
She's trying to build
a Soviet Firestorm.
Your comrade here tells
me you know quite a bit
내 연구에 대해
잘 안다더군
about this project of mine.
You're hanging us out to dry, Rip!
지원을 보내!
I need backup!
Half the team is gone.
팀의 절반이 잡혀갔어
I'm gonna remember that, comrade.
방금 거 기억하마
당신과 보스톡 박사는
할 일이 많아
You and Dr. Vostok have much
work to do in the morning.
Incredible.
멋지군, 새 파이어스톰 개발에
필요한 정확한 공식이야
This is the exact formula
for the thermocore that's
needed to build a new Firestorm.
How did you manage
to arrive at something
이걸 계산하기까지
얼마나 걸렸나?
that took decades to produce?
But here's what I don't understand.
하지만 새 파이어스톰은
기반이 불안정해요
The Firestorm Matrix is unstable.
The thermocore reacts exponentially
코어가 숙주의 핵분열을
기하급수적으로 증가시키거든요
to the rate of fission in the host body.
다행히
Well, fortunately, Dr. Wells
developed the Quantum Splicer
웰스 박사가 그 점을 해결할
양자 결합기를 개발했네
to address that very problem.
I-I'm so happy to see that
you're taking an interest
내 연구에 이렇게나
흥미를 보이다니 기쁘군
in my work.
당연하죠, 선생님
What can I say, sir?
Nuclear physics is my passion.
핵 물리학은
제 열정인걸요
"Sir"?
선생님이라고?
The Cisco I know never
dwelled on formality.
내가 아는 시스코는
격식을 갖춰 말하지 않아
What's more, your hair is different,
머리 스타일도 다르고
your wardrobe neat, your
comportment gentlemanly.
옷은 신사처럼
말끔하게 차려입었군
Oh, yeah, you like?
네, 마음에 들어요?
'GQ' 잡지 좀 봤죠
I just subscribed to "GQ""
Huh.
A snide attempt at humor...
유머 감각은
시스코와 닮았군
almost Cisco-like.
Almost.
거의...
What are you implying?
하고자 하는 말씀이?
What I am stating unequivocally, sir...
분명히 말하지만, 선생
is that you are not Cisco,
넌 시스코가 아니야
which means I am not in S.T.A.R. Labs.
그 말은, 여기도
스타 연구소가 아니야
Furthermore, I will never,
난 절대 네놈들에게
공식을 넘기지 않을 거다
never give you the formula.
Bravo, Professor Stein.
훌륭해요, 슈타인 박사
What cocktail of hallucinogens
have you given me, Doctor?
나한테
무슨 환각제를 준 건가?
Don't worry.
걱정 마세요
I would never dream of damaging
that beautiful mind of yours.
교수님의 뛰어난 두뇌를
해치는 일은 없으니까요
I simply want to open it.
들여다보기만 한 거예요
Finish the formula, and these
little games of ours can stop.
공식을 완성하고
이런 게임은 그만둡시다
그따위 속임수에
내 연구를 넘기지 않아
You'll never trick me
into giving up my research.
And since you also cannot kill me
파이어스톰 개발 때문이라도
날 죽이진 않을 테니
and destroy any hope of
creating a Soviet Firestorm,
I would like a hot shower
따뜻한 물에 샤워하고
옷이나 갈아입고 싶군
and a change of clothes.
And I thought I gave a good speech.
나만큼 말재주가 좋네
I'm sorry. Have we met?
우리 만난 적 있나?
11 years ago,
11년 전
you bought a nuclear
warhead off me in Norway.
노르웨이에서
내 핵무기를 사들이고
And then you and your
time-traveling friends
당신과 시간 여행자 일당이
날 죽이려 했지
tried to kill me.
Just like me, you haven't aged a day.
나처럼
나이를 안 먹었네
I have a good hairdresser.
내 미용사가
실력이 좋거든
In my long life, I have met some
지금까지 실력 좋은
심문관들을 만나 봤지만
of the most skilled
interrogators in history, but...
But since we are in the Soviet Union,
소련에 와 있는 김에
내 친구 자랑을 해볼게
let me tell you a story
about a friend of mine...
Joseph Stalin.
조세프 스탈린
He became quite skilled
at breaking a man...
고문하는 재주를
타고났더군
Carefully aimed strikes
to the bridge of the nose,
콧대를 잘 겨냥해
내려친 다음
along the shoulder blades,
어깨뼈와
턱을 작살내는 거지
and right underneath the chin.
Stalin gave me this as a gift.
스탈린이
선물로 준 거야
So it's to be torture, then?
고문을 하겠다?
Get on with it.
어디 해봐
No.
싫어
Nothing so prosaic for you, Professor.
그건 너무 평범해, 교수
There are infinite ways to break a man,
굴복시킬 방법은 많고
and I have an infinite amount of time.
나한텐 시간도 많아
Firestorm is my life's work.
파이어스톰은
내 평생의 연구야
I will never allow you to pervert it
네놈의 세계 정복에
쓰이는 걸 용납할 수 없다
in pursuit of global conquest.
This is going to be so much fun.
이거 흥미진진하겠군
S01E05 "Fail-Safe"
한글자막/싱크수정 : ㅇㅇ
Synced and corrected by sysrapmarvel
www.addic7ed.com
1986년, 소련 연방
_
Jefferson! Jefferson!
제퍼슨? 제퍼슨!
Jax?
잭스?
What are you doing in here?
여기서 뭐 해?
Hey, are you all right?
괜찮아?
Yeah, I, uh...
네, 이틀 동안
잠을 못 자서요
I haven't been able to
sleep the past two nights.
I prescribed Mr. Jackson
some mild medication.
제가 잭슨 군에게
순한 약을 처방했습니다
Which don't seem to
be doing a damn thing.
그딴 짓 하지 말랬지?
What's wrong?
왜 그래?
Ah, it's Stein.
슈타인 박사님이요
또 시작됐어요
They started in on him again.
He's scared to death. I-I can feel it.
교수님의 공포가
느껴져요
- He's trying to be strong,but...
- We're gonna get him back.
- 버티려고 하시는데...
- 우리가 되찾을 거야
Ray and Rory too.
레이와 로리도
I'm sure Captain Hunter has a plan.
캡틴한테
계획이 있을 거야
It's my fault he got captured.
교수님이 잡힌 건
내 탓이에요
If... if he wasn't
trying to protect me,
날 지키려다가
혼자 가신 거니까요
he would have never gone in there alone.
It's gonna be okay, Jax, I promise.
괜찮을 거야, 잭스
장담해
You don't know what kind of
place they got him locked up in.
납치된 장소가
어떤 곳인지 모르잖아요
Labor Camp Number 54...
강제 노동 수용소
54구역은
Formerly known as the Koshmar
or "Nightmare" gulag.
'카시마르' 또는
'악몽의 감옥'으로 알려져 있고
Built in the 18th century...
18세기에 건설되어...
Can we skip past the Wikipedia crap
위키피디아 헛소리는 됐고
침투하는 방법이나 말해
and get to the good stuff,
like how to break in?
Perhaps you didn't register
that as a question, Gideon.
그 질문에 대한 답변은
없나 봐, 기드온?
I understood, but in its
200 years of operation,
알겠습니다
하지만 200년 동안
탈옥의 전례가 없는...
no one has successfully escaped from...
No offense, Gideon,
미안하지만 내가
뚫지 못한 건물은 없어
but I never met a building
I couldn't break into.
Well, I hope you're right.
사실이길 바랍니다
Savage knows that
Stein created Firestorm,
새비지는 교수님을
개발자로만 알지
but if he finds out
that he is Firestorm...
교수님 자체가
파이어스톰이란 걸 알면
Always Savage with you, isn't it?
늘 새비지만 중요하지?
My partner's in prison too.
내 파트너도 갇혀 있어
- And Ray.
- Yeah, whatever.
- 레이도
- 아무튼, 너 때문에!
The point is you didn't lift a finger.
You know damn well it
was never my intention
내가 고의로 놔둔 게
아니란 거 알잖아요!
to get them thrown into a
gulag, but I had no other option.
마땅한 대안도 없었고요
Besides, I doubt that it's
Mr. Rory's first time in prison
게다가 로리 씨는
감옥에 열 번은 갔다 왔나?
or second or, I imagine, tenth.
All right, arguing is not
싸운다고 해서
팀이 돌아오진 않아
gonna bring the team back any faster.
And Rip's right.
립이 옳아
범죄자들에겐
감옥이 익숙하지
Criminals usually do feel
more at home in prison,
and they know it
better than anyone else.
누구보다도
그곳을 잘 알고
So?
- 그래서?
- 만약
So what if the key to breaking in
소련 감옥에 수감된 적 있는
죄수의 도움을 받는다면?
is asking someone who's been
in and out of Soviet prisons
their whole life?
And who might that be?
그게 누군데요?
Are you familiar with the Bratva?
'브라트바'란 자를 알아요?
Ooh, the Russian Mob?
오, 그 러시아 마피아?
In 1986, they would have
ruled the criminal underground
1986년도엔 교도소마다
지하 조직이 있었지
inside every prison.
Your tattoo.
그 문신
It stands for "Menia Ispravit Rasstrel"
'Menia Ispravit Rasstrel'라고
쓰여 있군요
if I'm not mistaken.
In English, it translates to,
"Execution Will Reform Me""
영어로 '사형은
날 교화시킬 것이다'
What brings you to the
banya, little man?
러시아 사우나엔
웬일이야, 말라깽이?
The name's Rip.
립이라고 합니다
I understand that you're familiar
카시마르 감옥은
익히 알죠?
with the Koshmar Gulag.
We need to break into that prison.
그 감옥에 침투해야 해
And can you make it fast?
I despise the heat.
난 더운 게 싫으니까
짧게 끝내
반달 새비지라는 작자가
그곳에서 비밀 작전 중이에요
A man by the name of Vandal Savage
runs a secret operation out of it...
A prison within a prison, if you will.
감옥 안의 감옥이랄까요
I've heard of this Savage.
새비지란 이름은
들어 봤지
He has no respect
내 나라의 범죄자 전통을
따르지 않는 놈이야
for my country's rich
criminal traditions.
우릴 도와줄 건가?
So you'll help us?
You men have no tattoos.
문신이 없는 놈은
And a man who has no life
story cannot be trusted.
인생이 없는 놈이니
믿을 수 없어
Igor! Andrei!
이고르! 안드레이!
Don't all volunteer at once.
한꺼번에 덤벼 보든가
Igor and Andrei seem
to be a bit preoccupied.
이고르와 안드레이는
바쁜가 보네요
Now, about that gulag...
자, 감옥 얘기로
돌아가서...
No matter.
상관없어
In this life, a man fights for himself.
죽기 전에
남자답게 싸워 봐야지
Perhaps you'd like this one.
당신이 나설 거죠?
He's all yours.
알아서 하세요
So you like having Vandal Savage
반달 새비지가 당신 나라에
악의 제국을 세우는 게 좋나 보죠?
run his evil empire from your country?
As much as a pig enjoys
being Christmas dinner.
성탄절 만찬을 즐기는
돼지만큼!
Help us, and we will
destroy his entire operation.
우릴 도와주면
놈의 조직을 파괴할게요
I just took out six men.
You guys couldn't handle one?
내가 6명을 때려눕힐 동안
한 명도 처리 못 해?
You killed my men?
네가 부하들을 죽였나?
They're not dead yet.
아직은 살아 있어
And neither are you,
assuming you help us.
우릴 도우면
당신도 무사할 거야
My organization runs black
market goods into Koshmar.
내 조직이 카시마르에서
암시장을 운영한다
Three of our, uh, well, comrades
우리 동료 셋이
그곳에 잡혀 있어요
are being held there by Savage.
Koshmar is not a hotel
for petty criminals.
카시마르는 피라미들한텐
안락한 곳이 못 돼
If your friends are there,
네 친구들이
거기 있다면
they must be insane, ruthless animals.
짐승들 틈에서
고생깨나 할 거야
Hey. Howdy.
안녕하세요, 반가워요
- How you doing?
- What the hell are you doing?
- 뭐 하는 짓이야?
- 인사하는 건데?
Just being friendly.
This must be where they keep the VIPs.
VIP용 감방도 있겠지?
여긴 교도소야, 멍청아
VIP따윈 없어
This is prison, jackass.
There are no VIPs.
Some of these guys have
been here for a while.
여기 오래 계신
분인가 봐
Hey, maybe this guy
knows where Stein is.
교수님이 계신 곳을
물어보자
누가 말하래!
빨리 움직여!
넌 교도소에서 보낼
밤이나 걱정해, 꽃미남
The only thing you should
be worrying about, Pretty,
is lasting the night.
Stein needs help. He's in real trouble.
교수님이 위험해
주위를 봐
우리도 마찬가지야
Newsflash, so are we.
Think they'll bring us blankets later?
이불은 나중에 주려나?
Now, according to Yuri,
유리 말로는 여기가
자기 부하가 있는 곳이래요
this is where his men have access.
Got it?
알겠죠?
This isn't my first prison break.
프리즌 브레이크가
처음도 아니야
- We got it covered.
- So how can we help?
- 알아서 할게요
- 어떻게 도울까요?
피해를 최소화해야 하니
우주선에 남아요
By staying on the ship.
We don't need any more casualties.
Besides, Mr. Snart and
Sara have got it covered.
- 스나트랑 새라가 가니까
- 잠깐만요
Whoa, man. Why does it feel like
언제부터 우리가
2군이 된 거예요?
we're on the JV team all of a sudden?
What you are is one half
of everything Savage needs
넌 새비지한테 필요한
전쟁 무기의 반쪽이고
to change the face of the Cold War.
And you are the only
person who can kill him.
당신만이 새비지를
죽일 수 있죠
Yeah, so you can't just...
그래도...
새비지가 원하는 두 사람을
손수 내줄 순 없어요
I am not going to gift
wrap the two people
in the world that Savage wants the most.
We should get going.
출발이나 하지
Oh, Ms. Lance, could I
borrow you for a moment?
랜스, 임무와 관련해서
알려 줄 게 있어요
I have something that might
help you out with the mission.
So what did you really
want to talk to me about?
진짜 용건이 뭐예요?
Gideon, will you please show
Ms. Lance the projection of 2016
기드온, 임무가 실패할 경우
2016년의 상황을 보여 줘
should our rescue mission fail?
I'd be happy to, Captain.
물론이죠, 캡틴
So this is what will happen to Russia
교수님을 구하지 못하면
러시아가 멸망하는군요
if we don't get Stein back?
러시아가 아니라...
Not Russia.
This is Star City.
스타 시티예요
The rest of world
doesn't look much better.
다른 나라들도
상황은 마찬가지고요
That's impossible.
말도 안 돼요
소련 파이어스톰은
교수님 아니더라도
Not if Stein creates a stable
Firestorm for the Soviets.
Here in 1986, they're
already perilously close
1986년, 벌써 소련이
완성까지 도달했어요
to creating a prototype.
Listen to me, Sara. Everything...
Everything we've tried
우리가 지금까지 한
노력이 물거품 돼요
to achieve so far could be lost.
And not only will my family
die 150 years from now,
150년 후엔
내 가족뿐만 아니라
but your family, your city...
당신의 가족과 도시...
your entire 21st-century
world will suffer.
21세기 전체가
고통받아요
That's why we're gonna get Stein back
그러니까
교수님을 되찾아야죠
before Vostok can break him.
보스톡이
굴복시키기 전에요
Well, I, I hope so, but
we need a contingency plan.
그러면 좋겠지만
사전 대책이 필요해요
What are you saying?
무슨 말이에요?
I'm saying that if at any
point throughout the operation
교수님을 구출할 가능성이
희박하다고 판단되면...
it becomes clear that Martin is...
beyond our reach...
You want me to kill Stein?
나더러 교수님을
죽이라는 거군요
DC 기타미국드라마갤러리
한글자막/싱크수정 : ㅇㅇ
Impressive how many weapons
you can fit in that outfit...
옷에 그 많은 무기가
들어간다니 놀랍네
And how much stupidity Raymond
can squeeze into this one.
레이먼드를 이 안에
구겨 넣는 건 얼마나 웃길까
The plan is to save him too,
not just Stein and your partner.
이건 레이도
구출하는 임무야
Oh, I'm gonna save Raymond, all right,
물론 녀석도 구할 거야
정신 차리게 때려 줘야지
so I can beat some sense into him.
- 넌?
- 내가 뭐?
And what about you? What about me?
너만 따로
임무를 맡은 것 같던데
Clearly I'm not the only
one with a side mission.
방과 후에
립이 뭐라고 속닥였어?
What did Rip keep you
after class to talk about?
세부 사항 몇 가지
알려 줬어
He just wanted to go over
a few details of the plan.
너한테 영감을
처리하라고 했지?
He wants you to take out
the old man, doesn't he?
It's the obvious play.
당연한 수순이지만
무정하기도 하네
It's also heartless.
The plan is to save Stein.
목적은 교수님을
구출하는 거야
만약 그러지 못할 경우
And if, for whatever reason, we can't,
Rip showed me what will
happen to my home in 2016,
립이 우리 가족에게 닥칠
2016년 상황을 보여 줬는데
to our families.
교수님이 굴복하면
그 피해가 막대해
If Stein breaks, the
damage is irreversible.
강도짓 하면서
힘들 때도 많았지만
Been on a lot of heists, and
even when things got rough,
내 손으로
동료를 죽인 적은 없어
I never took out one of my own.
Well, this isn't a bank heist.
이건 은행 털이가 아냐
처음엔 내 파트너를
버리고 오라더니
First, he left my partner
twisting in the wind.
이젠 너한테
동전 던지기를 시킨다?
Now he's gonna have
you ice old silver-top.
We're all just pawns, Sara.
우린 소모품이야, 새라
Come on, I'm the crook,
you're the assassin...
범죄자에 암살자...
죽이는 것뿐만 아니라
미래를 구하라고 했어
He's not just asking me to kill.
He's asking me to save the future.
And if, for whatever
reason, we can't save Stein,
교수님을 구할
여건이 안 되면
then I'm gonna do what needs to be done.
난 필요한 일을 할 거야
스카우트 캠프 같네
Huh. It's just like scout camp.
그곳 음식도 끔찍했어
Man, the food was terrible.
There was one time they
gave us Salisbury steak...
솔즈베리 스테이크가
나온 적 있는데
넌 입 다물 줄 모르냐?
You ever stop talking?
What I wouldn't give for a
little Salisbury steak now.
이걸 보니 솔즈베리
스테이크가 간절해진다
Hey. Ray Palmer.
레이 팔머라고 합니다
Put your hand down.
손 내려
He might know where Vostok
is keeping the Professor.
교수님이 갇힌 곳을
알지도 몰라
Shut up and eat.
조용히 먹기나 해
Do you know if there's any other place
죄수들을 가두는
다른 장소를 아세요?
where they keep prisoners here?
친구를 찾고 있는데
We're looking for a friend.
하나 있어
There is a place.
한번 가면
영영 못 돌아와
They send you there,
you never come back.
You can hear the screams all night.
밤새 비명이 들리지
어딘데요?
This place, where is it?
Who said you could eat?
누구 맘대로 처먹으래?
Hey, he's not hurting anybody.
점잖은 분이에요
Who is this American
with the pretty teeth?
앞니 가진런한
이 양키는 뭐야?
Must be a comedian, da?
코미디언이겠군
I'm sure we can handle this like adults.
어른답게 해결할까요?
이 새끼가!
Sooka!
I brought you something
to eat, Professor.
식사하세요, 교수님
뇌물이라면
정중히 거절하지
If this is a bribe, I politely decline.
고집불통에 도도하고
미국인답네요
So stubborn, so proud...
so American.
핵열 코어는
또 만들면 되잖나
You've already built a thermocore,
so just build another one.
8~10년 걸릴 걸세
It'll only take you eight to ten years.
그래서 코어를 훔쳐갔나요?
서방 국가를 구하려고?
You thought that, what,
your friends stealing
the thermocore would save the West?
한 개만
만들었을 리 없죠
As if I would only build one.
가까워졌어요, 교수님
We're so close, Professor.
코어를 안정화하는
방법만 알아내면
All I need to learn now is how
to stabilize the thermocore,
인간 핵무기라는
제 꿈이 이뤄지는 거예요
and my dream of creating a
nuclear man will be achieved.
뭐 때문에?
To what end?
소련 파이어스톰을
추진하면
If you launch a Soviet Firestorm,
미국은 보복할 거고
두 국가는 파멸에 이르게 돼
the United States will have
no choice but to retaliate.
Both countries will be annihilated.
잿더미 속에서
강하게 태어나는 거죠
And out of the ashes,
we will rise stronger...
나찌를
피침했을 때처럼요
just as we did when the Nazis invaded.
미국은 약해질 겁니다
But America is weak...
with your Big Mac, MTV,
movie-star president.
빅 맥, MTV
영화배우 대통령과 함께요
Do you really think Vandal Savage cares
반달 새비지가
냉전을 신경 쓸 것 같나?
about the Cold War?
그자는 박사를
이용하는 걸세
He's just using you, Doctor.
다시는 새비지 씨를
모욕하지 마세요
Do not think of insulting
Mr. Savage in front of me.
Hey, what's wrong?
왜 그래?
변화가 있어요
Something's changed.
Grey thinks we've abandoned him.
교수님은 우리가
버렸다고 생각해요
점점 포기하고 계시는데
난 못 참겠어요
He's starting to lose it in there.
I can't take this.
- 립한테 말하자
- 우릴 제외한 인간한테요?
We've got to tell Rip.
The guy who benched us?
He'll just tell us to sit tight.
가만히 있으라고 할 걸요
No, I hate feeling so helpless.
이런 무력감은 질색이에요
무릎이 박살났을 때도
이런 기분이었어요
This is exactly what it was
like when I blew out my knee.
I could barely walk,
recruiters stopped calling,
간신히 걷는데다
스카우트 연락은 끊기고
my mom always crying.
엄마는 울기만 하셨죠
I just wish there
was something I could do.
내가 할 수 있는 게
있으면 좋겠는데
Wait.
잠깐, 너랑 교수님은
텔레파시가 통하지?
Your connection with Stein,
it goes both ways, right?
Yeah.
네
그럼 신호를
보낼 수 있을 거야
So maybe we can send him a signal.
Grey did tell me about this
one time he and Ronnie...
로니랑 했던 걸
말씀하신 적 있어요
칼을 가져와서
내 피부에 표시해요
Get a knife. You need to cut me.
Tell me how to stabilize Firestorm.
안정화하는 방법을
말씀하세요
If Einstein had the opportunity,
아인슈타인도
기회만 있다면
과거로 돌아가 원자 폭탄
만드는 걸 막았을 텐데
he would have traveled back in time
to prevent the creation
of the atomic bomb.
How can I in good
conscience lead the world
하물며 내가 파괴적인
발명품을 세상에 내놓겠나?
to the invention of something
far more destructive?
You don't really have a choice.
선택의 여지가 없군요
이 독극물로는
죽진 않지만
This toxin, it's not lethal,
but it will make you wish that it were.
그렇게 되길
바라실 거예요
확실해?
Are you sure about this?
So, Professor...
자, 교수님
Would you like to talk, or
would you prefer to scream?
말씀하실래요?
비명을 지르실래요?
마음대로 하게, 박사
Do your worst, Doctor.
살아 있네, 네가 졌어
Hey, Pyro, what was that
there back in the yard?
파이로!
아까 그건 뭐였어?
교도소 먹이사슬이야
Just your typical prison alpha.
널 위협해서
1인자 자리를 유지한 거지
He didn't like you
threatening his reputation.
Not that. I mean you sitting there
아니, 내가 맞을 동안
구경만 했잖아
while I was getting my ass kicked.
내 알 바 아니지
None of my business.
None of your business?
네 알 바 아니라고?
We're... supposed to be a team.
우린 팀이어야지
팀은 나랑 스나트고
The only team I'm on
is mine and Snart's.
넌 맞을 짓을 했잖아
Besides, you had that beatdown coming.
Oh, well, I can't sit back
그 노인이 괴롭힘 당하는 걸
보고만 있을 수 없었어
and watch an old man get pushed around.
Then you're a bigger
fool than I thought.
내 생각보다
더 멍청하군
이놈들이다
These are the ones I want.
날 기억하나?
Remember me?
Identification papers.
신분증 꺼내 봐
불곰 유리가 보냈소
Yuri the Bear sent me.
교수님 먼저
구출하는 거야
Remember, we get Stein first.
실패하면
네가 죽이겠지
And if the plan fails, you'll kill him.
- You want my advice?
- No.
- 조언 하나 할까?
- 아니
총 대신 손을 써
Don't use your gun.
Do it with your hands.
영감을 죽일 땐
눈을 꼭 쳐다봐
Do it while you're looking
right into Stein's eyes.
교수님은 팀의 일원이야
You're talking about
a member of our team.
너야말로 그걸 잊지 마
I just don't want you to forget
who we're talking about.
고맙군
Thank you.
발렌티나가
입 여는 걸 실패했으니
Valentina has failed to make you talk.
Now it's my turn.
이제 내 차례야
Colonel, let's begin.
대령, 시작하죠
So are you still planning...
What did you threaten before?
아직도 생각이 있나?
'록키 4' 주먹을
꽂는다고?
To go all "Rocky IV" on my ass?
I've changed my mind.
생각을 바꿨어
이반 드라고는
영화 마지막에 살아 있거든
Ivan Drago lives at
the end of the movie.
Ha...
DC 기타미국드라마갤러리
한글자막/싱크수정 : ㅇㅇ
심문할 땐
원래 질문하는 거 아냐?
Isn't he supposed to
ask us some questions?
우리 입을
열려는 게 아니야
They don't care what we got to say.
We're just part of the show.
우린 쇼일 뿐이지
교수님...?
Stein.
Professor, we're okay.
교수님!
저희는 괜찮아요
놈들한테
아무 말씀 마세요!
Don't tell these bastards anything!
If you think I have a
sentimental attachment to them,
내가 감상적일 거라
생각했다면
you are as foolish as you are mad.
그 광기만큼
어리석은 걸세
예상보단 잘 버티는군
You held up longer than expected.
But if 4,000 years of life
has taught me one thing,
하지만 4천 년의 세월이
가르쳐 준 게 있다면
그건 인내심이야
it is patience.
When I get out of here...
- 내가 여기서 나가면...
- 그게 잘못된 거야
That is your mistake...
여기서 나갈
생각을 하다니
Thinking that you'll get out of here.
Hey.
어이
Can I get some water in here?
여긴 물 없어?
Something to drink?
I'm a little thirsty.
목이 말라서 말이지
A sandwich would be nice...
A little turkey and mayo.
샌드위치도 좋겠어
칠면조 고기에 마요
러시아에도 마요가 있나?
They have mayo in Russia?
No.
없다고?
At least in America,
you get a last meal.
미국이었다면
최후의 식사는 줄 텐데
공산주의는 형편없어
This Communism really sucks.
What are you doing, Boy Scout?
뭐 하는 짓이야
보이 스카우트?
그래, 보이 스카우트
뭐 하는 거지?
Yes, Boy Scout, what are you doing?
Nothing compared to what I
did to your mother last night.
내가 네 엄마랑
한 일에 비하면 별것 아냐
혀를 잘도 놀리는구나
You have quite a mouth on you.
So does she.
네 엄마도 그랬지
Enough! You're killing him!
멈춰! 저러다 죽겠어
That's it?
- 포기하는 건가요?
- 대령은 이제 시작일 텐데
Oh, but the colonel will
think that we are cheating him.
방법을 말할 테니
저들은 살려 주게, 제발!
I'll tell you how to
stabilize Firestorm.
Just let them live, please!
So how does it feel to be dead again?
다시 송장이 된
기분이 어때?
왼쪽으로 꺾어
Take the next left.
여긴 오면 안 돼, 동무
You can't be down here, comrade.
시체를 소각하라는
명령을 받았어
I was ordered to take this
corpse to the incinerator.
그러지 마
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
천연두 무기화 실험에
쓰인 시체거든
Dr. Vostok used him for one
of her smallpox weapons trials.
Highly contagious.
전염성이 높지
All right, this duct
should take us to solitary.
하수도를 따라가면
독방이 나올 거야
- 교수님한테...
- 난 안 가
- We get to Stein...
- Yeah, I'm not going.
- 그게 목적이야
- 립의 목적이겠지
- That's the plan.
- That's Rip's plan.
My priority is Mick.
내 최우선은 믹이야
좋아, 그러든지
Fine. Forget it.
범죄자 주제에
그놈의 규칙은
So much for your code, crook.
잘 해봐, 암살자
Anytime, assassin.
Of all the dumb things
I've seen in my life,
알아서 매를 벌다니
그런 멍청한 짓은 처음 본다
you getting that guy to
beat on you takes the cake.
고맙긴 뭘
You're welcome.
You think you proved
something back there?
뭘 증명하려고 했어?
두렵지 않다는 걸
보여 줬잖아
Proved I wasn't scared.
꼴 좋은 피냐타겠지
Proved you make a great pi?ta.
He could have beaten you to death.
죽을 때까지 맞았을 거야
살아 남는 것보다
중요한 게 있어
There are some things that are
more important than survival,
신념을 지키는 것...
like standing up for
what you believe in,
your principles, your team.
의리... 팀...
There must be something
you're willing to die for.
목숨을 바칠 만한 게
있기 마련이라고
The perfect score.
무식하면 용감하지
뭐...
Well...
용기의 기준이
서로 다른가 보네
only difference between us
is how we define "score."
I'm sorry to inform you, Captain.
안타깝지만, 캡틴
미국이 냉전에서
패배할 확률은 99%로
The probability of the United States
losing the Cold War has risen to 99%.
저항군의 중심지였던
스타 시티는 2003년 멸망합니다
Star City, the seat of the resistance,
is predicted to fall in 2003.
서둘러요, 새라
Come on, Sara.
You mentioned
전에 양자 결합기를
말씀하셨죠, 교수님
the Quantum Splicer earlier, Professor.
교수님의 선택에
친구들 목숨이 달렸어요
Your friends are counting on
you to make the right decision.
교수님을 확인했어요
I have eyes on Stein.
미래가 확고해지고 있으니
연구실로 가기 전에 구출해요
The future is cementing.
You must extract Stein
before he enters the lab!
Kill her!
여자를 죽여!
무슨 일이에요?
What's happening, Ms. Lance?
교수님을 못 구했어요
I couldn't rescue Stein.
Have they moved him into the lab?
그들이
연구실로 들어갔나요?
Yeah, where Savage has every guard
네, 새비지의 경비들이
감시하는 곳이에요
in the gulag watching him.
그렇다면...
Well, if that's the case...
I know what I have to do.
뭘 해야 하는지 알아요
DC 기타미국드라마갤러리
한글자막/싱크수정 : ㅇㅇ
The formula for stabilizing
Firestorm, Professor.
파이어스톰을 안정화시키는
공식이요, 교수님
This may surprise you, but in my youth,
들으면 놀라겠지만
내가 젊을 때
러시아에 방문했다가
I longed to visit Russia.
I was obsessed by your culture...
자네 나라 문화에
매혹됐었어
Rachmaninoff, Dostoyevsky, Tolstoy.
라프마니노프
도스토예프스키, 톨스토이
Stop stalling.
시간 끌지 마세요
It's a shame I, I never got to
see it before the collapse.
붕괴되기 전에
더 못 보는 게 아쉽군
그건 무슨 헛소립니까?
What sort of nonsense
are you talking about?
In 1991, your economy fails,
and your empire crumbles.
1991년, 소련의 경제
자네의 제국은 무너져
But the truth is the
world is better off.
대신 세상은 더 나아졌네
In my time, crooks and
thieves rule your country,
내 시절엔 범죄자들이
자네 나라를 이끌었지
desperate to hang on
to power and the riches
권력에 집착하고
부유층은 추종자들
사이에서 분열될 때
they divide amongst their cronies.
My country is by no means perfect,
내 나라는
완벽하진 않았지만
but at least we are free
to criticize our government,
적어도 정부를 비판할
자유는 있었네
vote in fair elections,
and love whom we choose.
공정한 투표로
선출된 지도자를 따랐어
I, uh, hate to break
this to you, Dr. Vostok.
이런 말하기 싫지만
보스톡 박사
You are on the wrong side of history.
자넨 엉뚱한 편에
서 있는 걸세
For now.
지금은 그렇겠죠
But you will help us change history.
교수님이 우릴 도와
역사를 바꿀 겁니다
Proceed.
시작하세요
Gideon, are you able to detect
기드온, 교수님의 생명을
원격으로 감지할 수 있나?
the Professor's life functions remotely?
Yes, Captain. His pulse is still strong.
네, 캡틴
맥박은 여전히 뜁니다
Yeah, not for much longer.
오래 안 갈 거야
Rip, Jax and I need to talk to you.
립, 잭스랑 내가
할 말이 있어요
Now is really not a good time.
적당한 때가 아닙니다
Yeah, this will only take a minute.
잠깐이면 돼요
I know you think you
can't risk losing us,
우릴 잃기 싫은 건 아는데
그건 실패했을 때의 경우죠
but that's assuming we'd fail.
And we won't.
우린 실패하지 않아요
I'm not afraid anymore.
더 이상 두렵지 않아요
난 할 수 있어요
I can do this.
And I don't got to be Firestorm
나도 팀에 일조하는
파이어스톰이 되고 싶어요
to be a part of this team.
Look, I am not prepared
to risk anyone else.
난 또 다시
잃을 준비가 안 됐어
- Ever since...
- Carter?
- 그날 이후...
- 카터요?
- His death wasn't your fault.
- I know.
- 당신 탓이 아니에요
- 알아요
But Stein's will be.
하지만 교수님은
내 탓이에요
All I got to do is touch him,
내가 교수님과 합체해서
날아오기만 하면 돼요
and we can fly out of there.
Yeah, once you've scaled a 50 foot fence
50피트짜리
철조망 담을 넘어서
topped with razor wire, gotten
past eight sharpshooters,
8명의 저격수들을 지나면
구소련 범죄자들과 마추칠 텐데?
and entered a gulag full of
the most dangerous criminals
in the U.S.S.R.
Okay, so you create a distraction,
당신이 주의를 끄는 동안
내가 잭스를 데리고 날면 돼요
and I'll fly Jax in,
and no one will see us.
Listen...
들어 봐요
선수가 모자라는데
경기를 뛸 순 없어요
you're playing chess without
all your pieces on the board.
Maybe you're right.
네 말이 맞을지도
So that's a "yes"?
동의하는 건가요?
You call that a flame?
라이터는 안 어울려
Ah. Nice costume.
- 의상 좋군
- 네 옷도 챙겼어
Got one for you too.
Wakey, wakey.
일어나, 작아져야지
Time to shrink... or not.
아님 말든가, 가자
- Let's go.
- What about him?
녀석은 어쩌고?
여기서 못 살아 남아
We can't ditch him. He won't survive.
Two guards walking out of
here... not suspicious.
경비 둘이 나가는 건
의심스러울 게 없지만
Two guards carrying
him out... suspicious.
녀석을 짊어지고
데려가는 건 의심스럽지
- 나 대신 맞아 줬어
- 얜 모르는 사람한테도 그래
He took a beating for me.
Raymond would take a
beating for a total stranger.
믹, 우리가 함께하는 동안
뭘 배웠어?
Mick, if our time in the
can taught us anything,
it's we look after each other.
우린 서로만 돌봐주면 돼
It's you and me, right?
여기로 들어가서
전압기를 차단하는 거야
So, if we enter here, we
can cut the circuit breaker.
Shutting off all the power.
전력을 끊는 거지
경비들을 방해해
시간을 벌 수 있겠네요
Distracting the guards and
giving us time to save our team.
작전이 성공할 확률은...
The probability of this
plan being successful...
저격수 탑의 전력이
차단되는 건 15초뿐이야
There is a 15 second window
where the sharpshooters on the tower
aren't covering the breaker.
110미터를 12초 만에
돌파해야 한다는 거네요
Which means that somebody
would have to run 120 yards
in less than 12 seconds.
하지만 잭슨 군의
십자 인대 파열이...
Given Mr. Jackson tore his
anterior cruciate ligament...
믿음을 가져 봐, 기드온
Have a little faith, Gideon.
넌 할 수 있어
난 알아
You can do this.
I know you can.
끝났네
It's done.
이렇게 간단한
정리일 줄 몰랐어요
You know, I've never
seen a theorem so simple,
그전엔 시 같았는데
so poetic before.
With this, I can decelerate
the subject's rate of fission
이걸로 실험 대상의
핵분열 상승과
and decrease core body temperature.
체온을
낮출 수 있겠네요
하지만 빠진 게 있어요
Yet something's missing.
이게 모든 문제를 해결할
양자 결합기의 등식이라니까
I'm telling you, that is the equation...
Everything you need to
build a Quantum Splicer.
"We're coming"?
'우리가 가고 있다'?
설명하세요
Explain.
- I cut myself.
- Impossible.
내가 그은 걸세
불가능해요, 교수님은
줄곧 감시당하고 있었는데...
You've been monitored ever
since your arrival here.
So, unless some...
So, unless someone else was cut,
yet it appears on your body...
다른 사람이 그은 게
교수님 피부에 나타난 거군요
- That's preposterous.
- No, no, no.
- 그건 말도 안 돼
- 불타는 남자와 연결돼 있어요
You are somehow connected
to the Burning Man.
That's how you were able to absorb
그래서 핵 에너지를
흡수할 수 있었군요
the nuclear energy at Luskavic.
잘못 안 걸세
You are mistaken.
파이어스톰을
개발했을 뿐만 아니라
No, You didn't only create Firestorm.
교수님이 파이어스톰의
반쪽이에요
You are one half of Firestorm.
- 헛소리!
- 코어를 가동해
That's ridiculous!
Bring the core online.
And to think, all this time..,
그동안...
교수님이 열쇠였어요
- you were the missing link.
- Listen to me.
완벽하게 호환이 되는
두 사람이 필요한데다
It is extremely rare to find
two people who are compatible,
양자 결합기 없인...
and without the Splicer...
여성과 결합해
보신 적 있나요, 교수님?
Have you ever merged
with a woman before, Professor?
우리가 합체하면
I think you and I are gonna
make a wonderful Firestorm.
원더풀한 파이어스톰이
될 것 같군요
DC 기타미국드라마갤러리
한글자막/싱크수정 : ㅇㅇ
저 둘은 왜 왔어요?
What the hell are they doing?
What I should have
done from the start...
시작한 걸 끝내야죠
교수님을 구출합시다
Helping rescue Stein.
- 미래는 어쩌고요?
- 계획이 있어요
What about the time line?
I have a plan.
Forget about the fail-safe.
안전책은 잊어요
Isn't it a little late for plan C?
플랜 C를 실행하기엔
늦지 않았나요?
잭스가 전압기까지
가기만 하면 돼요
Not if Jax can reach
that circuit breaker.
이 멍청이 때문에
목숨을 걸다니!
I can't believe you're risking
your life for this idiot.
Okay, okay.
좋아, 할 수 있어
You got this.
필드 12초 달리기...
수백 번도 해봤잖아
12 seconds, open field...
Done it a million times.
Ah!
Barry Allen who?
배리 앨런이 누구라고?
Electromagnetic locks.
전자 잠금이 풀렸어
우린 경비 차림이잖아!
We're dressed as guards.
Run.
뛰어
다들 감방으로 돌아가!
Everyone back in your cells!
Enjoy your new cellmate!
새 감방 동료랑
잘 놀아라
안 돼!
No!
That door leads to the loading bay.
저 문으로 나가면 주차장이야
가서 우주선에 올라타
From there, you can
get to the jump ship.
믹, 이렇게 안기는 건
또 처음이네
Hey, Mick, this is a
strange kind of hug.
- 넌 어디 가는데?
- 할 일이 있어
- Where are you going?
- I got something to do.
새비지 씨
헬리콥터로 가시죠
Mr. Savage, I need to
get you to the helicopter.
Make sure the Professor
enters the reactor.
교수를
원자로까지 데려가
His nuclear-mate is waiting for him.
새 동료가
기다리고 있으니
Take the core to full power.
전출력으로 가동해
There seems to be a riot going on.
폭동이 일어난 것 같은데
명령을 재고해 보게
You might want to
reconsider your orders.
Vostok knows Stein is the
other half of Firestorm.
보스톡이 교수님의 정체를
알아내서 결합하려고 해요
She's trying to merge with him.
Rip, once Stein is inside the reactor,
립
교수님이 원자로에 들어가면
소련 파이어스톰이 되고 말아요
he will become Soviet Firestorm.
Do you copy?
I have the shot.
쏠 수밖에 없어요
- Sara, don't do it.
- I don't have a choice.
새라, 쏘지 마
어쩔 수 없어
스타 시티를 구해야 해
It's the only way to save Star City,
the future.
미래를...
그건 살인자들 짓이지
That's how a killer thinks.
And that's not you anymore.
넌 더 이상 아니잖아
Our energy...
우리의 에너지가...
하나가 되길
갈망하고 있어요
It yearns to be whole, Professor.
Uh, without the Splicer...
양자 결합기 없인...
Aah!
Without the Splicer, you'll
never be able to control
양자 결합기 없인
핵반응을 조절할 수 없어
our nuclear reaction.
내 말 듣게, 박사
You have to listen to me, Dr. Vostok.
융화되지 못하면
우리 둘 다 죽어!
Unless we un-fuse, you'll
end up killing us both!
립 헌터는 어리석군
Rip Hunter must be a fool
널 내 품으로 보내다니
to send you into my arms.
Come with me, Chay-Ara,
나랑 가자, 셰이아라
and I will find a way
to prolong your life.
네 수명을 연장해서
영원히 함께하는 거야
We will live together in eternity.
No.
싫어
싫어?
No?
내 대답은
언제나 거절일 거야
My answer will always be "no."
Go.
가요
날 또 죽이게?
You want to kill me again?
질리지도 않나, 가리브?
Doesn't this game ever get
too old for you, Gareeb?
It's Captain Hunter, if you don't mind.
캡틴 헌터라고 해
Oh.
난 파이어스톰 개발을
막으러 온 거야
I'm here to make sure you
never build a Firestorm...
and for my watch, actually.
시계도 되찾을 겸
1975년, 피의 의식을
치를 때 빼앗아갔잖아
You stole it from me
during a pagan blood ritual
back in 1975.
기억나?
Ring any bells?
Ah, ah.
천천히
Slowly.
난 널 죽일 생각 없어
I have no desire to kill you.
넌 살아서
I want you alive.
세상이 불타는 걸
지켜봐야 하니까
I want you to see the world burn.
지난 11년 동안
네 처자식의 사진을 봤다
I have looked so often
at your wife and son
these last 11 years...
미란다와 조나스
Miranda and Jonas,
둘의 얼굴이
선명하게 새겨졌지
their faces etched into my mind.
And when I finally get to meet them,
네 가족을 만나면
너와 네 친구들 때문에
고통받는 거라고 말해 주마
I will let them know
that you and your friends
are responsible for their suffering.
Not if I see you first.
내가 널 먼저 만나면
얘기가 달라지지
그쪽은 어떻게 돼가요?
How's it going up there?
Sara? Sara, are you there?
새라, 들려요?
Now you're on the comm?
드디어 응답하는군요
We need to get out of here.
여길 빠져나가야 해요
Whoa! Don't shoot! Grey's in there!
쏘지 마요!
교수님이 안에 계세요
방법이 없군
Lot of good it would do anyhow.
- 될 대로 되라지!
- 뭘 어쩌게?
Man, screw this!
What are you doing?
I'm getting Stein back.
교수님을 되찾으려고요
We'll cover you.
우리가 엄호하지
그 안에
계신 거 알아요!
I know you're in there, Grey!
And he's begging for
you to save yourself.
너한테 도망가라고
애걸하는구나
댁한테 말한 거 아냐
I wasn't talking to you.
슈타인 교수님께
말씀드린 거야
I was talking to Professor Stein.
교수님의 정신력은
저 여자보다 강해요
Your mind is stronger than hers, Grey.
절 엄하게 대하셨던
이유를 알아요
I get it. I know why
you've been so hard on me.
You're trying to protect me.
로니처럼 잃게 될까 봐
절 보호하신 거잖아요
You don't want to lose
me like you lost Ronnie.
And that's why I know you're
not gonna let her kill me.
절 죽이게
놔두시진 않을 거예요
제 머릿속에
늘 계셨기 때문에
'Cause I've had you inside of my head,
교수님이 얼마나
강한 분인지 알거든요
and I know what a tough, old
son of a bitch you can be.
여자를 이겨내세요
So you got to fight
her, because you and me,
교수님과 제가
파이어스톰이니까요
we're Firestorm, Grey.
교수님과 저요!
You and me!
Jefferson!
제퍼슨!
- 괜찮나?
- 교수님은요?
- You okay?
- Yeah, you?
- 괜찮아
- 오래 못 가요
Yeah.
Not for long.
I tried to warn her. Without
the Splicer and myself,
경고했었네
양자 결합기와 나 없인
핵 에너지가 불안해진다고
her nuclear powers are
dangerously unstable.
보스톡 박사는
녹아내릴 거야
It appears Dr. Vostok is
having a bit of a meltdown.
이거... 흥미롭군
It's... it's fascinating.
교수님 말씀은
피하라는 뜻이야
I think what he means to say is "run."
I'll have the jump ship
우주선을
정문에 대기시킬게요
waiting just beyond the main gate.
DC 기타미국드라마갤러리
한글자막/싱크수정 : ㅇㅇ
Courtesy of Yuri the Bear.
불곰 유리한테 고맙군
이런 걸 훔칠 여유는
어디서 난 거야?
How did you even have
time to steal this?
훔칠 여유는 늘 있어
There's always time to steal.
Thank you.
고마워, 그리고...
And just so you know,
I know you're more than just a thief.
자넨 도둑보다
나은 사람이야
You took a beating for me.
나 대신 맞아 준 걸
갚은 거야, 얘기 끝
We're even. End of story.
Well, thank you.
고마워
More drinking, less feeling.
마시고 털어 버려야지
역사를 안 망친 걸
첫 기념하며 건배하지
A toast to the first time
we haven't completely
ruined the time line.
사실이라고 해 줘
기드온
Please tell me that's true, Gideon.
The projections of the
future are back to normal.
미래는 다시 정상입니다
- I'll drink to that.
- To Rip.
- 그럼 마셔야지
- 립의 계획이
차질 없이
진행된 것을 위해
To things not going
according to his plan.
- To the Captain.
- 캡틴을 위해
- 좋아요
- 잠깐, 자네 21살 아니잖아
- All right.
- Hold on, Jefferson.
- You're not quite 21.
- Yo...
In 1986, the drinking age
in Russia was 12, so...
1986년 러시아에선
12살 때부터 술을 마시니까
뭐, 이번엔 봐주지
오늘 자넨 영웅이었네
Well, perhaps we can let
it slide this one time.
After all, you were the hero today.
- You saved my life.
- Oh, that?
- 내 목숨을 살렸어
- 그거요? 별일 아니에요
That was no biggie.
러시아의 미친 과학자와
결합하고 나니
Having merged with an
insane Russian scientist,
자네를 파트너로 둔 게
얼마나 행운인지 모르겠군
I now know how lucky I am
to have you as my partner.
Partners.
파트너를 위해
교수님께선 모르시죠?
Stein doesn't know, does he?
That I almost killed him?
내가 죽이려 한 거요
내가 부추겼잖아요
That I advised you to kill him.
이상해요
It's funny.
리그 오브 어쌔씬에
있을 땐
When I was in the League of Assassins,
암살 실패는 용납할 수 없는
죽음보다 비참한 일인데
failure to follow through
on a hit was unforgivable,
a thousand times worse than death.
Maybe I'm losing my edge.
판단력을 잃어가나 봐요
Or gaining a new one.
새로운 걸 얻었거나요
The fact that you didn't pull
the trigger speaks volumes.
결국 방아쇠는
당기지 않았잖아요
냉전은 역사에 맡기고
교수님을 죽이는 게 안전했어요
You know, the safe
move was to kill Martin
with the Cold War
hanging in the balance.
I would like to think
it was your humanity
인간성을 잃지 않은
덕분이라고 생각할게요
that stayed your hand.
I'd like to think that too,
but I had some help.
나도 그렇게
생각하고 싶지만
도움이 컸어요
What was that?
뭐야?
폭발성 발사 무기에
맞았습니다
We have been struck with
an explosive projectile.
- 농담이지?
- 다들 벨트 장착해요!
- No kidding.
- Everyone get strapped in now!
We're in the Temporal Zone.
I don't understand.
여긴 차원 구역이라
우릴 쫓는 게 불가능한데
No one should be able to...
확실해?
You were saying?
상대는 현상금 사냥꾼인
크로노스입니다
A scan of the vessel
suggests that it is the
bounty hunter Chronos.
이 자식은
꼭 이럴 때 나타나네
Oh, man, this guy has impeccable timing.
우릴 쫓아옵니다
He appears to be following us.
대응 발사 개시
Firing countermeasures.
Countermeasures effective.
격추 성공
따돌렸나?
Have we lost him?
네, 하지만
미사일은 아닙니다
Yes, but not his missile.
후미 쪽 방패가
위험합니다
Our aft shield is gravely compromised.
Initiating evasive maneuvers.
비행이 어지러울 거예요
아, 보드카 괜히 마셨어
Ah! The vodka was a bad choice.
Impact in three, two, one.
충격까지 3, 2, 1
Sir, we've just been knocked
out of the timestream.
방금 타임스트림에
떨어졌습니다
무슨 뜻이에요?
What does that mean?
추락한다는 뜻이에요
It means we're crash-landing
어떤 시간대의 장소로요
in place and time.
Gideon, camouflage the ship.
기드온, 우주선을 위장해
This doesn't look like the type of place
우주선이 노출되면
안 될 장소 같군
we want to linger out in the open.
That looks a lot like
a Palmer Tech building,
저건 팔머 테크
건물 같은데
but why does it have a Smoak logo on it?
스모크 로고는 뭐지?
Wait. This is Star City.
여긴 스타 시티예요
I thought you said
the time line was safe.
미래는 무사하다면서요?
Yeah, Star City was intact in 2016.
네, 2016년의
스타 시티는 온전해요
여긴...
This...
2046년이에요
this is 2046.
Don't move!
움직이지 마!
Oh, thank God.
- 다행이야
- 움직이지 말라고 했다
I said don't move.
나야
It's me.
It's Sara.
새라
Hey, Oliver, look,
올리버
오래 전 일이지만
I-I know it's been a long
time, but don't you remember
립 헌터가 레전드
모집한 거 기억 안 나?
that Rip Hunter recruited
us to become legends?
난 레전드따윈 몰라
I never heard of any legends.
Synced and corrected by sysrapmarvel
www.addic7ed.com
DC 기타미국드라마갤러리
한글자막/싱크수정 : ㅇㅇ